Finding aid for Blanchard Family Papers, ca. 1835-ca. 2000
Bentley Historical Library
- Nathan A. Cobb
  - Visual Materials
    - Negatives, glass plate
      - 3" by 4", circa 1890-1910
        - Yeo and Jones, Messrs., 4 negatives (Box 17)
        - Yosemite National Park, California, 10 negatives (Box 17)
        - Yuba Mountains, California (Box 17)
        - Zebra (Box 17)
      - 4" by 5", undated
        - Fly (Box 17)
        - Postage stamps (possibly Korean) (Box 17)
      - 4.5" by 6.5", circa 1890-1910
        - Bong Bong, New South Wales, Australia
          - Bong Bong River, 2 negatives (Box 18)
          - Laboratory, 3 negatives (Box 18)
          - Laboratory, exterior, 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Children (possibly Cobb family)
          - Holding hands, in a circle, in front of a house (Box 18)
          - Pulling one another in a wheeled chair (Box 18)
        - Cobb family
          - Alice V.
            - In hat, under tree (Box 18)
            - Reclining, with issue of Vanity Fair magazine, 2 negatives (Box 18)
          - Nathan A.
            - With William Farrer (bearded) (Box 18)
            - With Mr. Wills and William Farrer, 2 negatives (Box 18)
          - Ruth and Dorothy (portraits) (Box 18)
          - Victor (Box 18)
            (Cobb's note: "First plate; none with hat")
        - Coleman, Miss (portrait on horseback) (Box 18)
        - De Satis, Leo (Box 18)
          (youth, running)
        - Greenwood, Proctor, and Cobb group (Box 18)
          (Joseph Greenwood was a noted New England painter)
        - Grosse, E.M. (Box 18)
        - House (unidentified), 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Kuring-gai: study (Box 18)
        - Lambrigg (experimental farm and residence of William Farrer) (Box 18)
          (photograph includes Queanbeyan, the house where the Cobb family resided while Nathan studied wheat with Farrer)
        - Microscope table (designed by N. A. Cobb), 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Palm trees (Hawaii), 6 negatives (Box 18)
        - Proctor family portrait, 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Pymble, New South Wales, Australia (Box 18)
        - San Francisco, California: Golden Gate Park, 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Spencer, Massachusetts
          - Proctor place, 2 negatives (Box 18)
          - Town farm, 2 negatives (Box 18)
        - Sydney, New South Wales, Australia
          - Circular Quay (Box 18)
          - George Street (Box 18)
          - Ship at dock in harbor (Box 18)
        - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm, New South Wales, Australia
          - Manure experiments with late-sown wheat, 5 negatives (Box 18)
          - Tall tripod (in use) invented by Cobb to photograph large wheat plots (Box 18)
          - Views on farm, 2 negatives (Box 18)
          - Wheat plots, 5 negatives (Box 18)
          - Vineyard (view from laboratory) (Box 18)
        - Worcester, Massachusetts
          - 30 Maynard Street
            - Interior, with children, 3 negatives (Box 18)
            - Interior, with Roger and Victor Cobb playing with stone ships (Box 18)
          - Tramway Street Sprinkler Car, 2 negatives (Box 18)
    - Photographs
      - Albums
        - Alaska, circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
        - Algeria, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - Australia
          - 1890s-1900s (Box 19)
          - Kuring-gai (Cobb family residence in New South Wales, Australia), circa 1890s (Box 19)
        - Australia and Massachusetts, circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
        - Belgium and Eng, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - California, circa 1898-1900; 2 volumes (Box 19)
        - Europe, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - Florida, circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
        - France, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - Germany and Northern Europe, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - Massachusetts and Australia, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 19)
          (includes Cobb family portraits)
        - Massachusetts (Worcester), circa 1898-1900; 2 volumes (Box 19)
        - Massachusetts (Woods Hole) and Mary, undated (Box 19)
        - Samoa, Hawaii, and San Francisco, circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
        - Scandinavia, circa 1899-1900 (Box 19)
        - Southwestern United States
          - Mostly Texas, circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
          - With images from Oklahoma, New Orleans, Virginia, etc., circa 1898-1900 (Box 19)
        - United States (various cities including Spencer, Massachusetts and San Francisco, California), circa 1898-1900 (Box 20)
        - Washington D.C. (include images from other U.S. locales and Samoa), circa 1898-1900 (Box 20)
        - Western United States (Salt Lake City, Yellowstone, Pike's Peak, etc. with additional scenes from the Midwest), circa 1898-1900 (Box 20)
      - Australia
        - Camp kitchen (possibly at Bong Bong, New South Wales), circa 1890s (Box 20)
        - "The Governor at Hawkesbury" (an agricultural college), circa 1890s (Box 20)
        - Hawkesbury Agricultural College, 1900s (Box 20)
        - Hearwood (laboratory and environs), circa 1890s (Box 20)
        - Lambrigg (experimental farm and home of William Farrer), circa 1890s-1900s (Box 20)
        - Mt. Wellington, undated (Box 20)
        - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm (public tour or presentation), circa 1890s (Box 20)
        - Wheat field (possibly Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm), circa 1890s (Box 20)
        - Wheat varieties, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 20)
      - Europe
        - Agricultural practices (various locations), circa 1899-1900 (Box 20)
        - City (unidentified) with mountains in background, undated (Box 20)
      - Hawaii
        - Cobb (Nathan) and W. E. Chambers in the field (Kauai), circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Hawaiian Sugar Planters' Association (HSPA) Experiment Station building, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Hawaiian Sugar Planters' Association (HSPA) Experiment Station staff, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Landscapes, seascapes, buildings, and people, circa 1905-1907; 2 folders (Box 20)
        - Native fishermen, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Plants (various): close-up images, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Residence of Cobb family (various views), circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Ships and harbor, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
        - Sugarcane cultivation (plants, fields, production technology mills, and laborers), circa 1905-1907; 4 folders (Box 20)
        - Sugarcane diseases, circa 1905-1907 (Box 20)
      - Portraits
        - Children (on swing), undated (Box 20)
        - Cobb, Nathan A.
          - Undated (Box 20)
          - 1864 (Box 20)
          - 1873 (Box 20)
          - 1877-1879 (Box 20)
          - 1880-1889 (Box 20)
          - 1890s-1900s (Box 20)
          - 1920s-1930s, 2 folders (Box 20)
        - Farrer, William, circa 1900 (Box 20)
      - Other
        - City scenes (various unidentified), undated (Box 20)
        - Cobb family residence in Falls Church, Virginia, circa 1910s-1930s (Box 20)
        - Insects (various), undated (Box 20)
        - Laboratory interiors (various, unidentified), undated (Box 20)
        - Photomicrograph, undated (Box 20)
        - Steam ship (unidentified), undated (Box 20)
    - Positive glass plate images
      - 3" by 4", circa 1890-1930
        (includes lantern slides and plates of different sizes)
        - Aleuron cells, 3 plates (Box 21)
        - Bird observations
          (N. A. Cobb became heavily involved in the study and observation of blue jays at his home in Falls Church, Virginia. These hand-colored slides were used in his presentations on "Jack and Jill.")
          - Blue jays, 11 plates (Box 21)
          - Cobb family residence in Falls Church, Virginia, 6 plates (Box 21)
          - Cobb, N. A.: various positions of observation and study, 9 plates (Box 21)
        - "Clark position" (Box 21)
          (humorous image of a man (Cobb?) in a "Lewis and Clark" exploratory pose)
        - Cobb family
          - Alice V. and child (Frieda?) (Box 21)
          - Family portrait (Alice and children), 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Frieda (Box 21)
          - Margaret and Frieda on an outing with female help (Box 21)
          - Nathan A. (in laboratory), 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Roger, Victor, and Frieda (Box 21)
          - Victor (Box 21)
        - Combined harvester (Box 21)
        - Denny, Joe (Box 21)
        - Flies
          - Close-up, head, 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Dorsal view, 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Eye (possibly), 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Ventral view, 2 plates (Box 21)
        - Hawaii
          - Landscapes
            - General, 2 plates (Box 21)
            - With building (Box 21)
            - With man (Box 21)
            - With woman (Box 21)
          - Lily pads, 2 plates (Box 21)
          - Luau (Box 21)
          - Map of islands (Box 21)
          - Palm trees
            - General, 2 plates (Box 21)
            - With man (Box 21)
          - Study (or laboratory) of N. A. Cobb (Box 21)
          - Vegetation, 3 plates (Box 21)
        - Insect (unidentified) (Box 21)
        - Larva (unidentified): diagram with notes (Box 21)
        - Nematodes
          (also referred to as "nema" by Cobb)
          - Measurements (Box 21)
          - Slide set (possibly for lectures or presentations), 14 plates (Box 21)
          - Typical specimens (possibly for lectures or presentations), 11 plates (Box 21)
        - North Dakota: harvesting (Box 21)
        - Pen and ink drawing reproductions, 9 plates (Box 21)
        - Pineapple
          - Cross section (Box 22)
          - Longitudinal section (Box 22)
        - Pymble, New South Wales, Australia, 5 plates (Box 22)
        - "Riding the Rebel" (reproduction of a horse-riding scene) (Box 22)
        - Seed drill (probably taken at the Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm) (Box 22)
        - Ship at dock (Box 22)
        - Spencer, Massachusetts: Bisco place (Box 22)
        - Statuette (possibly from the Adelaide Botanical Gardens) (Box 22)
        - Street scene with electric streetcars (unidentified city) (Box 22)
        - Sugarcane disease, 2 plates (Box 22)
        - Taemia Echinococcus (Box 22)
        - Tobacco fields: Amherst, Massachusetts (Box 22)
        - Tropical scenes, 16 plates (Box 22)
          (colored plates that May have been used in a public presentation; possibly from the Caribbean or Panama)
        - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm, New South Wales, Australia: Laboratory (Box 22)
      - 4.5" by 6.5", circa 1890s-1900s
        - Boronia (Australian evergreen shrub) (Box 23)
        - Lambrigg (experimental farm and residence of William Farrer) (Box 23)
        - Wagga Wagga Experimental Farm, New South Wales, Australia: wheat stalks (Box 23)
- Alice Vara Cobb
  The Alice Vara Cobb series richly illustrates the domestic sphere of women in nineteenth century Australia and the United States. It includes extensive correspondence received by Alice Cobb from her husband, children (Victor, Frieda, Dorothy, Ruth, and Margaret), other family members, and friends as well as diaries and assorted personal papers and biographical materials.
  - Correspondence (unarranged): letters received from family members and others (Box 24)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): letters received from family members and others (Box 25)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): letters received from family members and others (Box 26)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): letters received from family members and others (Box 27)
  - Biographical material (Box 28)
    - Daughters of the American Revolution application, undated (Box 28)
    - Personal remembrances ("As I remember it"), 1940s (Box 28)
    - State Normal School (Worcester, Massachusetts) record of graduates, 1914 (Box 28)
  - Clippings, 1917-1939 (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, 1880s; 1940s; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Diaries
    - 1882-1895 (Box 28)
    - 1896-1897 (Box 28)
    - 1898 (Box 28)
    - 1920 (Box 28)
    - 1922 (Box 28)
    - 1924 (Box 28)
    - 1927-1943, 16 volumes (Box 28)
    - 1945-1946 (Box 28)
    - 1948-1949 (Box 28)
  - Household finance records, 1880s-1890s (Box 28)
  - Obituary (draft), 1951 (Box 28)
  - Professional
    - Dyer School (photograph) (Box 28)
    - Grade books, 1878 (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 28)
    (biographical material and correspondence)
- Frieda Cobb Blanchard
  The Frieda Cobb Blanchard series highlights their creator's professional accomplishments, artistic skills, education, and personal life in Australia, Hawaii, and Michigan. Materials include drawings and sketches, memorabilia from her youth, topical files and manuscripts related to scientific endeavors, and ample correspondence (unarranged and also grouped by date and name) with friends, family members, and professional acquaintances. In addition to her teaching responsibilities, genetics research, and work at the University of Michigan's Botanical Gardens and elsewhere, professional materials and correspondence detail Frieda Blanchard's collaboration with her husband, Frank, and other scientists.
  - Education: grade / high school / college
    - Sketchbooks, 1904-1905; 2 volumes (Box 29)
    - Course notes -- U.S. History, 1906-1907 (Box 29)
    - Essays, 1910 (Box 29)
  - Early materials sketches and memorabilia, 1900s; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with Cobb family relatives (Box 29)
  - Personal Correspondence from friends, A-Z (Box 30)
    (include letters from individuals and organizations in foreign countries relating to charitable giving)
  - Early materials (Box 31)
  - Topical files (Box 31)
  - Reprints of writings (Box 31)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 31)
    (includes biographical material and some correspondence)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): professional and personal matters (Box 32)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): largely personal letters from various friends and family (Box 33)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): largely personal letters from various friends and family (Box 34)
  - Correspondence (unarranged): largely personal letters from various friends and family (Box 35)
  - Correspondence files: professional and personal matters (Box 36)
  - Clippings (Box 37)
  - Correspondence
    - By Date
      - Undated (Box 37)
      - Prior to, 1935 (Box 37)
      - 1935 (Box 37)
      - 1936 (Box 37)
      - 1937, 2 folders (Box 37)
        (includes letters of condolence regarding the death of Frank N. Blanchard)
      - 1938 (Box 37)
      - 1939 (Box 37)
      - 1940-1942 (Box 37)
      - 1943-1944 (Box 37)
      - 1945-1947 (Box 37)
      - 1948-1950 (Box 37)
      - 1955 (Box 37)
    - By Name
      - Adams, Arthur (Box 37)
      - Allen, Dr. & Mrs. Edward (Box 37)
      - Ameel, Donald (Box 37)
      - American Society of Ichthyologists and Herpetologists, 1940-1944 (Box 37)
      - Arnold, Byron, 1935-1942 (Box 37)
      - Bargyla Rateaver Wagnon, 1945 (Box 37)
      - Bassett, W. K. (Woof) (Box 37)
      - Becker, F. C. and Starrett, M. R. (Box 37)
      - Blanchard, F. E. (Box 37)
      - Bliss, Grace (Box 37)
      - Bogert, Charles M., 1941 (Box 37)
      - Bonar, Lee & Margaret (Box 37)
      - Chambers, Annie, 1937-1940 (Box 37)
      - Chase, Ethel (Box 37)
      - Chipman, John & Ruth (Box 37)
      - Choate, Helen (Box 37)
      - Clover, Elzada (Box 37)
      - Cole, June (?) (Box 37)
      - Conant, Roger, 1938-1948 (Box 37)
      - Dana, Minnie L. (Box 37)
      - Davis, Bradley M. (Box 37)
      - Flower, Stanley S. (Box 37)
      - Force, Edith, 1938-1946 (Box 37)
      - George, Ira (Box 37)
      - Gilreath, Ruthie (Box 37)
      - Gloyd, H. K., 1937-1948 (Box 37)
      - Grobman, Arnold, 1941 (Box 37)
      - Hankinson, Nettie D. (Box 37)
      - Harris, Mildred, 1937 (Box 37)
      - Hatt, Robert T., 1940-1944 (Box 37)
      - Hinds, Frank (?), 1941 (Box 37)
      - Hines, Wallace, Goff, Walker, Clay, 1938-1939 (Box 37)
      - Janaki (Box 37)
      - Jerwich, Catherine (Box 37)
      - Kelly, Howard A., 1938-1941 (Box 37)
      - King, Ralph (Box 37)
      - Kiskey, Fred & Harold C. Bold, 1940-1942 (Box 37)
      - Löding (Box 37)
      - MacFarlane, Eileen (Box 37)
      - MacLeod, Ethyl (Box 37)
      - Margaret & Sue (Box 37)
      - Mason, Abbie Daniels (Box 37)
      - Nelson, Theodora, 1925-1944 (Box 37)
      - Netting, M. Graham, 1929-1947 (Box 37)
      - Neubecker, F. A. (Box 37)
      - Nolan, Conrad & Clara (Box 37)
      - Oliver, James A., 1947 (Box 37)
      - Pirnie, Mrs. Miles (Lucy) (Box 37)
      - Robbins, Nettie Leigh (Box 37)
      - Roberts, Edna (Box 37)
      - Ross, Bill, 1936-1939 (Box 37)
      - Ross, Ruth (Box 37)
      - Sawyer, Ella (Box 37)
      - Schmidt, Karl P., 1940-1942 (Box 37)
      - Thoms, Edith (Box 37)
      - Velasquez, Gregorio, 1936-1946 (Box 37)
      - Walker, Grace (Box 37)
      - Ward (Box 37)
      - Whipple (Box 37)
  - Manuscripts (includes collaborations with Frank N. Blanchard) (Box 38)
  - Snake files (Box 38)
  - Correspondence (Box 38)
  - Personal papers (various) (Box 39)
- Frank Nelson Blanchard
  The Frank Nelson Blanchard series provides insight into the personal and professional spheres of this noted herpetologist and instructor. Correspondence (arranged by date or correspondents' names) focuses largely on professional matters and the University of Michigan subseries documents Blanchard's role as a well-liked university professor. Publications contain additional information on his research and professional activities and the subseries also includes a list of Blanchard's works and manuscripts of various writings. The Personal/Miscellaneous subseries further reflects the active nature of Blanchard's mind; in addition to biographical materials, educational records, and obituaries, it contains notebooks of his observations on a variety of flora and fauna. Blanchard was also a conscientious diarist and the thirty-five volumes in the Diaries subseries offer a complete record of his daily activities from 1905 through his death in 1937. Finally, photographs and drawings depict Blanchard's family and friends as well as his research activities at the University of Michigan Biological Station and elsewhere in the United States. These visual materials are also indicative of Blanchard's close collaboration with his wife in that they include drawings of snakes made by Frieda Cobb Blanchard and photograph albums compiled by the two.
  - Correspondence
    - By Date
      - Undated (Box 40)
      - 1911 (Box 40)
      - 1915 (Box 40)
      - 1916 (Box 40)
      - 1917 (Box 40)
      - 1918 (Box 40)
      - 1919 (Box 40)
      - 1920 (Box 40)
      - 1921 (Box 40)
      - 1922 (Box 40)
      - 1923 (Box 40)
      - 1924 (Box 40)
      - 1925 (Box 40)
      - 1926 (Box 40)
      - 1927 (Box 40)
      - 1928 (Box 40)
      - 1929 (Box 40)
      - 1930 (Box 40)
      - 1931 (Box 40)
      - 1932 (Box 40)
      - 1933 (Box 40)
      - 1934 (Box 40)
      - 1935 (Box 40)
      - 1936 (Box 40)
      - 1937, 2 folders (Box 40)
    - By Name
      - Allen, Morrow J. (Box 40)
      - Anderson, Edgar
      - Anderson, W. W. (Box 40)
      - Antivenin Institute of America (Box 40)
      - Ball, E. W. (Box 41)
      - Barbour, Thomas (Box 41)
      - Bevan, W. A. (Box 41)
      - Bilsing, S. W. (Box 41)
      - Bishop, S. C. (Box 41)
      - Blanchard family (various) (Box 41)
      - Bogart, Charles M. (Box 41)
      - Boyer, Dorothy A. (Box 41)
      - Brigham, Reed O. (Box 41)
      - Brodie, Laura (Box 41)
      - Brown, Elmer E. (Box 41)
      - Brown, J. Roland (Box 41)
      - Burt, Charles E. (Box 41)
      - Cagle, Fred (Box 41)
      - Cahn, Alvin R. (Box 41)
      - Carney, J. T. (Box 41)
      - Clanton, Wesley (Box 41)
      - Clay, Bill (Box 41)
      - Cobb, N.A. (Box 41)
      - Cochran, Doris (Box 41)
      - Conant, Roger (Box 41)
      - Condon, Nellie Louise (Box 41)
      - Corrington, J. D. (Box 41)
      - Dakan, E. L. (Box 41)
      - Davis, Frances H. M. (Box 41)
      - Deviney, Ezda M. (Box 41)
      - East, C. S. (Box 41)
      - Eppenberger, Charles D. (Box 41)
      - Evans, Philip D. (Box 41)
      - Flower, Stanley (Box 41)
      - Force, Edith R, 3 folders (Box 41)
      - Frierson, L. S. Jr. (Box 41)
      - Gilmore, Esther E. (Box 41)
      - Gilreath, Ruth (Box 41)
      - Gloyd, Howard K. (Box 41)
      - Goff, C. C. (Box 41)
      - Gordon, Clarence E. (Box 41)
      - Greenhall, Arthur M. (Box 41)
      - Grinnell, Dr. Joseph (Box 41)
      - Guild, William (Box 41)
      - Guthrie, J.E. (Box 41)
      - Haire, Anne (Gilbert)
      - Hansen, E. E. (Box 41)
      - Harper, Francis (Box 41)
      - Harpster, Hilda (Box 41)
      - Hawkes, Louise (Box 41)
      - Hibbard, Claude W. (Box 41)
      - Jewell, Minna E. (Box 41)
      - Jones, J. Paul (Box 41)
      - Jones, Walter B. (Box 41)
      - Kelly, Howard, M.D. (Box 41)
      - King, Ralph T. (Box 41)
      - Kinghorn, Roy (Box 41)
      - Kirn, Albert J. (Box 41)
      - Klauber, L. M. (Box 41)
      - Knoll, Charles Maximilian (Box 41)
      - Kuster, Kimber C. (Box 41)
      - Lane, Alfred C. (Box 42)
      - LaRue, George R., 2 folders (Box 42)
      - Lewis, Owen Ellis (Box 42)
      - Lloyd, Alfred H. (Box 42)
      - Löding, H. P. (Box 42)
      - Logier, E. B. Shelley (Box 42)
      - Loveridge, Mr. Arthur (Box 42)
      - Ludwig, Dr. Clinton A. (Box 42)
      - MacIntyre, Thelma (Box 42)
      - Maria, Niceforo (Box 42)
      - Moe, Henry Allen (Guggenheim) (Box 42)
      - Mosauer, Walter (Box 42)
      - Mulaik, Stanley (Box 42)
      - Necker, Walter L. (Box 42)
      - Netting, M. Graham (Box 42)
      - Noble, G. Kingsley (Box 42)
      - Okkelberg, Peter (Box 42)
      - Ortenberger, A. I. (Box 42)
      - Papworth, A. G. (Box 42)
      - Parker, H. W. (Box 42)
      - Parker, Malcolm V. (Box 42)
      - Parks, H. B. (Box 42)
      - Patch, Clyde L. (Box 42)
      - Piatt, Jean (Box 42)
      - Piersol, William Hunter (Box 42)
      - Pope, T. E. B. (Box 42)
      - Quillin, Ellen Schultz (Box 42)
      - Reighard, Jacob (Box 42)
      - Ruthven, Alexander G. (Box 42)
      - Sanders, Earl
      - Schmidt, Karl P. (Box 42)
      - Science Press (Box 42)
      - Sherman, Franklin (Box 42)
      - Shockley, Clarence (Box 42)
      - Shoebridge, Evangeline (Box 42)
      - Shull, A. Franklin (Box 42)
      - Shull, Elizabeth (Box 42)
      - Smith, Mrs. H. H. (Box 42)
      - Smith, Hobart M. (Box 42)
      - Smith, Maxine (Box 42)
      - Stimson, A. C. (Box 42)
      - Stoll, Norman R. (Box 42)
      - Storer, Tracy I. (Box 42)
      - Strawn, Julian E. (Box 42)
      - Strecker, John K. (Box 42)
      - Svihla, Arthur (Box 42)
      - Swanson, Gustav (Box 42)
      - Switale, C. L. (Box 42)
      - Tanner, Vasco M. (Box 42)
      - Taylor, E. H. (Box 42)
      - Taylor, Walter P. (Box 42)
      - Turner, H. S. (Box 42)
      - Uhler, Francis M. (Box 42)
      - Van Cleave, H. J. (Box 42)
      - Van Huysen, Karl R. (Box 42)
      - University of Michigan -- Dean of Graduate School (Box 42)
      - Viosca, Percy Jr. (Box 42)
      - Wales, Robert (Box 42)
      - Welch, Paul S. (Box 42)
      - Wetmore, Alexander (Box 42)
      - Whitney, Daniel D. (Box 42)
      - Wiley, Grace D. (Box 42)
      - Woodbury, A. M. (Box 42)
      - Wooldbridge, Mary E. (Box 42)
      - Wright, A. H. (Box 42)
      - Yeatter, Ralph E. (Box 42)
      - Zoological Society of London (Box 42)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 42)
  - Diaries
    - 1901-1903 (Box 43)
      (includes cash accounts and miscellany)
    - 1905-1937, 34 volumes
      (includes a book of cash accounts and work records for 1912)
  - University of Michigan
    - Course and research materials (Box 44)
    - Course materials
      - Zoology 60 (Box 45)
      - Zoology 151 (Box 45)
      - Zoology 152 (Box 45)
      - Various (Box 45)
    - Dept. of Zoology (Box 45)
    - Zoological Journal Club reports, 1916-1917 (Box 45)
  - Personal / Miscellaneous
    - Biographical (Box 46)